waters.com 2018-09-02

# Privacy Notice : Waters

WATERS CORPORATION PRIVACY NOTICE

Effective Date: May 25, 2018   
Last Updated: May 25, 2018

This Privacy Notice describes how we collect, use and share information about you and how you can manage your privacy preferences. **BY VISITING OUR SITES OR USING OUR SERVICES, YOU CONSENT TO THE PRACTICES AND TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE.**

**WHO WE ARE**

We are Waters Corporation and its affiliated companies (collectively, “ **Waters** ”). This Privacy Notice applies to www.Waters.com and our other websites, mobile apps, and digital properties that link to or expressly adopt or refer to this Privacy Notice (we call these our “Services”).

**WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

“Personal Data” means any information that can be used to identify you, directly or indirectly, as an individual person. We collect Personal Data about you when you use our Services, including data provided by you, data we automatically collect, and data we obtain from third parties.

**Data Provided By You**

We collect Personal Data that you enter on our Services or give to us in another way. For example:

  * When you register with us online, we collect 
    * contact information, such as your name, email address, mailing address, and telephone number
    * employment-related information, such as employer, department, job title and business contact information
    * account information, such as account name, password, security question responses, a unique identification number, and discount eligibility
    * product interest information, including products and areas of interest, and “favorited” purchases
  * When you purchase a product or service from us, we collect 
    * purchase information, including payment card information, order details, government identification number, automated order entries and other transaction information
  * When you submit a job application to us, we collect 
    * employment application information, including contact information, employment and education history, and other information you include in your CV/resume or application materials
  * When you fill out a survey, we collect your response, which, depending on the type of survey, may include 
    * satisfaction with Waters, a Waters product or a Waters service
    * opinions on the design and usability of our Services, as well as Waters products and software
    * information about the market, products you use today and your thoughts about the future
  * When you contribute information to our websites, we collect user generated content, such as content you post on our forums or other Services, including reviews and feedback on Waters products
  * When you contribute information to our mobile applications, we collect information relating to your product needs
  * When you contact us on the phone, or through email, text, or chat, we collect the inquiries or reports you make and the content of your voice

**Data We Automatically Collect**

We use technologies to collect data automatically when you use our Services that do not directly reveal your identity. Examples of these technologies include the following:

> _Logging_ : Like most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP address, approximate location, browser type, operating system, internet service provider, the pages visited, operating system, clickstream data and time and date of visit.
> 
> _Cookies, Analytics and Other Data Collection Tools:_ We and third parties we work with use cookies, web beacons, local shared objects (or Flash cookies), and similar tools to collect and store data about your preferences and how you interact with our Services. For more information, including on how to control your privacy settings and your ad choices, read our [Cookie Policy](http://www.waters.com/waters/en_US/nav.htm?cid=134982469).

**Data We Obtain from Third Party Sources**

We collect information about individuals from a number of third party sources.

> _Business Partners and Service Providers:_ Our business partners and service providers, such as payment processors and analytics providers, collect Personal Data and share some or all of this information with us. For example, we receive Personal Data from vendors to identify potential employment candidates, to coordinate events and programs, to facilitate survey activities, to identify prospective customers and to conduct marketing and analytics.
> 
> _Publicly Available Sources:_ We collect Personal Data about you that we do not otherwise have (including contact information, employment-related information and product interest information) from social media platforms (for example, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn and YouTube), blogs (for example, WordPress), and other publicly available databases.

**HOW WE USE PERSONAL DATA**

We use the Personal Data that we collect to provide you the products and services you request, offer you other of our products and services, manage your account, process and evaluate job applications, communicate with you, develop new products and services, improve our products, business and services, and understand our customers. For example, we use Personal Data that we collect to:

  * Process and complete your transactions including, as applicable, order confirmation, registration for our programs or events, product selection assistance, and delivering products, programs, events, or services
  * Carry out our contractual obligations to you
  * Communicate with you about programs, products, or services we believe may be of interest to you
  * Tailor our products and services to you and your computer or mobile device
  * Allow you to participate in interactive features of our Services, when you choose to do so
  * Conduct market research to help us understand trends and customer needs across product categories or customer groups, allow you to create and maintain customer profiles, analyze your interactions with us, present customized offers, and improve our products, services, programs, events, and other offerings
  * Process and evaluate job applications you submit through the Services and communicate with you about your job applications and requests
  * Prevent, investigate, or provide notice of fraud, unlawful or criminal activity, or as otherwise required by law
  * Enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements

**HOW WE SHARE AND DISCLOSE PERSONAL DATA**

We share Personal Data in the following ways.

> _Within Waters:_ We share Personal Data within Waters for purposes and uses that are consistent with this Privacy Notice. For example, sharing Personal Data about you to process and fulfill your order, facilitate communication between you and a local Waters representative, and coordinate necessary data retention. 
> 
> _Service Providers:_ We share Personal Data with third-party service providers who complete transactions or perform services on our behalf, such as payment processing, shipping, processing employment applications, coordinating events and conferences, facilitating seminars and training courses, collecting survey responses, conducting marketing, market research, analytics, and verification. 
> 
> _Website and Mobile App Hosting Providers:_ We use multiple web and mobile app hosting providers to host our Services. In connection with providing those Services, our web and mobile app hosting providers have access to Personal Data about you collected through the relevant Service and may use the information consistent with the terms of its privacy notice. 
> 
> _Advertising Networks:_ We also share information you provide us with advertising networks, such as search engines, and social media platforms, to serve targeted ads to you on third-party platforms. For more information, including how to opt out of interest-based advertising, read our [Cookie  Policy](http://www.waters.com/waters/en_US/nav.htm?cid=134982469).
> 
> _Legal Process, Safety and Terms Enforcement:_ We may disclose Personal Data to governmental regulatory authorities in response to their requests for such information or to assist in investigations. We may also disclose Personal Data to third parties in connection with claims, disputes or litigation, when otherwise required by law, or if we determine its disclosure is necessary to protect the health and safety of you or us, to protect against fraud or credit risk, or to enforce our legal rights or contractual commitments that you have made. 
> 
> _Business Transfers:_ We may disclose Personal Data as part of a corporate business transaction, such as a merger, acquisition, joint venture, or financing or sale of company assets, and may transfer Personal Data to a third party as one of the business assets in such a transaction. It may also be disclosed in the event of insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on any affected Service of any change in ownership or uses of Personal Data, as well as any choices you may have regarding Personal Data about you.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Our Services are not directed to, and we do not intend to, or knowingly, collect or solicit Personal Data online from children under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, do not provide us with any Personal Data either directly, on any website forums, or by other means. If a child under 18 has provided Personal Data to us, we encourage the child’s parent or guardian to contact us to request that we remove the information from our systems.

**SECURITY OF PERSONAL DATA**

We have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures intended to protect Personal Data. Of course, we cannot guarantee that interactions with the Services will not be unlawfully intercepted or that your personal data will not be unlawfully accessed by third parties. You can also take additional measures to protect yourself and your information, such as keeping confidential log-in credentials and passwords.

**HOW TO UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION AND DATA RETENTION**

You may contact us to update information we have about you as set forth in the **How to Contact Us** section below. We will retain Personal Data for as long as necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice (for example, if you have an account, for as long as your account is active or as reasonably useful for commercial purposes).

**COUNTRY/REGION-SPECIFIC DISCLOSURES**

The laws of certain countries and regions require specific information to be included in a privacy notice. Please click below to review country/region-specific information applicable to you.

  * If you are a resident of the European Economic Area, [click here](http://www.waters.com/waters/en_US/nav.htm?cid=134982465).

**EMPLOYEES AND APPLICANTS**

We maintain a separate privacy notice for our employment-related data practices. Employees should read the Employee Privacy Notice for additional information regarding these employment-related data practices.

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

Some of our Services contain links to websites and digital services operated by third parties. This Privacy Notice does not apply to these websites.

Our Services also include features like buttons and widgets hosted by other companies (for example, the Facebook “Like Page” button). Some of these features collect Personal Data or other information such as IP address and your actions on our Services. This Privacy Notice does not apply to the practices of these third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy notices of those third parties to learn about their personal data and privacy practices.

**USER GENERATED CONTENT**

Some of our Services enable users to submit their own content for contests, forums, videos, and other functions. Please remember that any information you submit or post as user-generated content to our Services may become public information. You should exercise caution in such submissions or posts. We cannot prevent others from using such data in a manner that may violate this Privacy Notice, the law, or your personal privacy and safety. We are not responsible for the results of such postings.

**UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE**

This Privacy Notice will be revised as required. If we make any changes in the way we use Personal Data, we will post notice of the changes on our Services. The updated notice will be effective as of the Effective Date listed at the start of this Notice. You can determine when this Notice was last revised by checking the Last Updated date at the start of the Notice.

**MANAGING COMMUNICATION PREFERENCES**

If you have opted in to our marketing communications (or where permitted by law, if you have provided us or we have obtained your contact information), we may send you email messages, direct mail offers, push notifications or other communications regarding products or services depending on the method of communication selected. You may ask us not to do so when you access our Services, or change your preferences by updating any accounts you have with us. At any time, you may elect to discontinue receiving commercial messages from us by following the unsubscribe instructions in the form of the communication you received or by submitting an opt-out request to the contact information set forth in the **How to Contact Us** section below.

> _Printed Materials:_ To opt out of receiving printed marketing materials at your postal address, such as advertisements, flyers or postcards, please submit an opt-out request to the contact information set forth in the **How to Contact Us** section below. Please be sure to include your name and mailing address exactly as they appear on the printed marketing materials you received.
> 
> _Emails:_ To opt out of receiving marketing communications via email, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email that was sent to you or submit an opt-out request to the contact information set forth in the How to Contact Us section below. Please note that you may continue to receive certain transactional or account-related electronic messages from us.

**HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice or other privacy-related matters, please contact us in the following ways:

Waters Corporation  
Attention: Data Privacy  
34 Maple Street  
Milford, Massachusetts 01757
